# **SYARIFUDDIN FAKHRI A**

Syarifuddin is a student of Informatics in Institut Teknologi Bandung (ITB) and an IT specialist in TTL ID. He spent most of his time to studying Informatics and making a dancing robot for a National Robotics Contest. He is interested in UI/UX, web development, software development, and robotics.

Date of Birth: August 15, 2000

Gender: Male

### **EDUCATION**

### **BSc Informatics, Institut Teknologi** Bandung

2018 - Present GPA until 8th semester 2.83/4.00.

### Science course, SMA Negeri 1 Surakarta

2015 - 2018

Average of school report 88.57/100.

### **CONTACT**



+62 896 8200 2341



syarifuddinfa@gmail.com



linkedin.com/in/syarifuddinfa



github.com/sfa119f



# **SOFTSKILL**

- Teamwork
- Decision making
- Management
- · Easy adapted
- Leadership
- Critical thinking

# **COMPUTER SKILL**

- MS Word
- Draw.io
- MS Excel
- Figma
- MS Powerpoint

# **PROGRAMMING SKILL**

### FE Engineering:

- BE Engineering: Node.js
- Vue.js · React.js
- Go
- Laravel
- PHP

### ML:

### Mobile Dev:

Python

Android

# Robotic:

- Other:
- Arduino
- SQL • C/C++/C#
- Teensyduino
- Robotis
- Java

# **LANGUAGE**

- English
- Indonesian
- French
- Javanese

# **WORK EXPERIENCE**

### IT Specialist, Team Tanpa Les Indonesia (TTL ID)

2020 - Present. As an IT specialist, my main responsibility is making website and maintaining it. My specialty as a front-end developer.

## Front-End Intern, PT Fintek Teknologi Digital

2021 - 2022. As a front-end intern, my main responsibility is making front-end website and integrate with API.

# Developer, Project Student and Alumni Service for STEI ITB

2021. As a developer, my main responsibility is making system student and alumni service like legalizing documents and making document for it.

#### ORGANIZATION AND EVENT EXPERIENCE

### Member, Unit Robotika ITB

2019 - Present. As a member, my main responsibility is coding program, making robot dance moves, and maintaining robot. My specialty as a dance robot programmer.

# Participant, Baparekraf Developer Day 2021

Here I learn how to make Android TV applications, improve web performance, machine learning, and modern application architecture.

# Chief executive, Widyakelana Back To School 2020 (WBS 2020)

As a chief executive, my main responsibility is leading team, making and deciding concept the event and maintaining event. I am successfully collected 500 of tryout participants and more than 20 of school tours.

### **Event Organizer Staff, OSKM ITB 2019**

As an event organizer staff, my main responsibility is maintaining event before, during, and after OSKM. My job specialty is managing study orientation and faculty introduction. I also collaborated with around 30 mentors for supervise mentoring activities.

### Ticketing Staff, Widyakelana Back To School 2019 (WBS 2019)

As a ticketing staff, my main responsibility is controlling and maintaining registration website and making system for re-registration.

#### Vice Chairman, Majelis Kerohanian Islam Senior High School

2016 – 2017. As a vice chairman, my main responsibility is collaborating with chairman to lead team, mediating every meeting, and monitoring every event. My specialty as an internal management.

# **ACHIEVEMENT AWARD**

2021 - 3rd winner of Tokopedia Goes To Campus x Project, Tokopedia

2020 - Finalist of Kontes Robot Seni Tari Indonesia, Kemdikbud

2017 - 3rd winner of IT-VENTURE, Universitas Sebelas Maret

2017 - 2<sup>nd</sup> winner of Computer Olympiad region Surakarta, Kemdikbud